<body>
            <h1>After Carotid Artery Stenting: In the Hospital</h1>
            <p>
               <img alt="Healthcare provider checking patient’s pulse in hospital bed."
                    height="240"
                    width="300"
                    imageid="341022"
                    title=""/>After carotid artery stenting, you will most likely stay overnight in the hospital for care and monitoring. At home, follow your doctor’s instructions for recovery. Be sure to keep your medical appointments. This includes any imaging tests and other follow-up treatments. They can help make the procedure successful.</p>
            <Section>
               <h2>Just after the procedure</h2>
               <p>After the procedure, you can expect the following:</p>
               <ul>
                  <li>
                     <p>You will be taken to the recovery room for observation.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>A nurse will monitor your vital signs, your neurological signs, and the injection site while you are in the recovery room.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>Once your blood pressure, pulse, and breathing are stable and you are alert, you may be taken to the intensive care unit (ICU) or a regular hospital room.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>If the sheath was left in the insertion site, it will be removed from the groin or arm at the appropriate time. </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>After the sheath is removed, pressure will be applied by a nurse directly to the site either manually or with a clamp-type device for about 20 minutes. After bleeding has stopped completely with the pressure application, a tight dressing will be applied on the site.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>You may need to keep your leg straight for 2 to 6 hours.  It is very important that you keep your leg or arm with the catheter site straight during this period.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>You may be given pain medicine for pain or discomfort related to the injection site or having to lie flat and still for a prolonged period. </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>After the period of bed rest has been completed and there is no bleeding from the injection site, you may get out of bed. The nurse will help you the first time and will check your blood pressure while you are lying, sitting, and standing. </p>
                  </li>
               </ul>
            </Section>
            <Section>
               <h2>Your hospital stay</h2>
               <p>While you are in the hospital, you can expect the following:</p>
               <ul>
                  <li>
                     <p>You’ll be closely monitored until you’re ready to go home.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>Hospital staff will check your pulse, blood pressure, and neurologic function from time to time.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>You may also have tests of your brain function, blood tests, or an ultrasound.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>Your IV will remain in place until shortly before you go home.</p>
                  </li>
               </ul>
            </Section>
            <Section>
               <h2>When can you can leave the hospital?</h2>
               <p>Most people leave the hospital the next day. You can go home when:</p>
               <ul>
                  <li>
                     <p>Your condition is stable.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>You do not have weakness or numbness in either your legs or arms.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>The groin insertion site is not bleeding or swollen.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>You have no signs of infection.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>You have no headache or swings in your blood pressure or pulse. </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p>Your doctor has reviewed any test results and has cleared you to go home.</p>
                  </li>
               </ul>
            </Section>
         </body>
     